# **Patrick Lyons**

# **Electrical Engineer / LabVIEW Developer**

Oreland, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Patrick-Lyons/ced06c8d1c20b4e4

I have experience and understanding of engineering principles necessary to design and apply a variety of technologies in consumer/industrial devices or systems. From intelligent automation software architecture, retro-fitting CNC machines, PCB design, to rebuilding motorcycle engines, I have chosen my career path out of a passion for complex engineered systems, their design, implementation, and overall operation.

In my career as an engineer, I intend to never stop learning more efficient and effective ways to participate in creative solutions to problems of interest. From the simple and mundane to the complex and chaotic, there is always an opportunity to learn something new.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Electrical Engineer/LabVIEW Developer**

In-Phase Technologies - Bordentown, NJ - September 2011 to Present

Responsibilities

Facilitate the design, development, deployment, and maintenance of automated test systems utilizing embedded/industrial platforms including networking, programming, user interface design, and remote static/dynamic control.

### **Engineer Team Leader**

Radwell International - Lumberton, NJ - 2009 to 2011

Responsible for managing a team of technicians to troubleshooting and repair of industrial electronic devices including PLCs, induction & servo motor drives, and various PCB based control system devices.

# **Manufacturing Engineer**

Boehringer Laboratories - 2009 to 2009

responsible for maintenance and repair of various

production machines including ultrasonic welders, heat presses/stamps, etc.

## **Engineering Technician (GS-0802-4)**

NSWCCD Code 966 (Naval Surface Warfare Center Carderock Division - Philadelphia, PA - 2008 to 2009

Responsible for testing and troubleshooting

Nav/Control systems, as well as PCB design and construction of developmental projects.

#### **Research Assistant**

Temple University - Philadelphia, PA - 2008 to 2008

designing/prototyping a 2DoF Robotic arm utilizing McKibben actuators. Responsible for product research, construction, and testing.

#### Research Assistant

Temple University - Philadelphia, PA - 2007 to 2008

Under Dr. Li Bai designing a COTS based Contactless SmartCard Ticketing system for SEPTA. Responsible for Hardware troubleshooting, product research, and integration.

# **Quality Assurance Tester**

Aviom, Inc. - West Chester, PA - 2006 to 2006

Responsible for testing alpha products for networking issues, also gained experience in SMD soldering and product construction

#### **EDUCATION**

# **B.S.** in Electrical Engineering

Temple University College of Engineering 2003 to 2008

# **Certificate in Electronics Engineering Technology**

Eastern Technical School - Willow Grove, PA 2002 to 2003

**SKILLS** 

Resume in PDF format available upon request!

**LINKS** 

https://www.linkedin.com/in/plyons215

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

# Open architecture for contactless smartcard-based portable electronic payment systems.

http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/freeabs\_all.jsp?arnumber=4626497

Li Bai, Gerald Kane, and Patrick Lyons. In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Automation Science and Engineering (CASE), 23-26th August 2008.